so less than a year ago i diagnosed
myself with autism in spring 2019 and so
this is that story and a bit of the
magic that makes me autistic so a couple
years before that you know I'd say 2017
I got undiagnosed with a DD by my doctor
at the time who said I wasn't able to
get the meds unless I was read I ignored
as an adult so I went through the
process which is weird because I felt
like she had taken away a piece of my
identity I didn't really care to us to
start about the meds it was like you
can't be autistic
I'm sorry you can't be a DD unless you
are characterized as I I knew my whole
life I was a DD it's my brain that I've
lived in and dealt with my whole life
and so in getting read iagnosed or they
DD which did end up happening I ended up
mistakenly taking a questionnaire on
autism and without knowing that it was
very clear I was whatever this
questionnaire was was telling me I was
and then at the top was like oh it's all
tests that's why it's not the same that
there was just qualities that I did not
associate with a DD and so in so doing
it gave me the inkling the like little
spark of like maybe you're autistic the
straw that broke the camel's back the
thing that they pushed it over the edge
was somebody who tweeted out a list of
maybe you're autistic if and there were
so much it just resonated with me on
this deep-down level that I was in tears
and I was like these are my people
these this is what I've been dealing
with my whole life it's not just a DD
and it's also not just my brain changes
what would be known as brain damage from
my my brain tumors and resulting
treatments it is something that now
looking back I can see my whole life my
sensory issues when I was a child my
being overly emotional as a child
needing to turn it off being able to
feel other people's emotions which is
more of an empath thing but a lot of
autistic people also have
part of it it's like feeling other
people's emotions and not being able to
make sense of them not being able to
name your own emotions feeling like
clothes if if clothes were itchy or
scratchy they were never worn again I
didn't care how much money I spent on
them if shoes gave me a blister one time
they were never getting worn again and
now that I can embrace that and not feel
like I'm a broken female because I'm not
into fashion like right Comfort comfort
always Trump's fashion for me it's just
always is not for my kid though she
still needs it to be comfortable she
also wants it to be beautiful and cute I
don't my sensory stuff did get worse
after my brain tumors but I always had
it I remember wanting to like stab my
brother with a fork when he would chew
with his mouth open at breakfast and I
was not I was like a very happy bubbly
child but the sensory stuff would make
me go off I would have a tantrum well
into my teenage years if I had to wash
the dishes and there was peanut butter
in it I didn't know how to verbally
communicate that it was just like well
you're being a baby like so up it's not
a big deal everyone else is doing it you
just don't you just don't want to I can
look back now with hindsight and see how
my special I've had special interests
come and go for my life but two of the
two of mine that I've had my entire life
that are also they're both more socially
acceptable than a lot of what other
people special interests are but I've
had this urge to learn about human
atrocity the things that humans have
done to each other throughout history as
well as the beauty the environmental
catastrophes the the animals suffering
the the genocides and Wars and that's
less socially acceptable to bring up but
it because it's intertwined with
everything else it is somewhat socially
acceptable I'm more socially acceptable
now well you still should be probably
breakups you know these these type of
things that bring the mood down in and
one of my masks is laughing all the time
and I don't even know how to not do that
one that one I don't know how to unmask
and maybe I will at some point in time
in their moments when I can
but I think it helps me learn about the
atrocities because it has an actual
neurological effect on my body to be in
a happy mood almost all of the time and
so I was able to learn about these
things that depress other people and yet
underlining I think that's where a lot
of my chronic health issues come from is
knowing about all these things and
feeling alone in that knowledge that
like people just don't want to hear
about it they don't want to know they
don't want to solve it and I get why
because it's overwhelming and then the
other special interest is me it's like
Who am I
how do I fit into the world and through
that how do other people fit into the
world how does how do things work for
other people what makes me unique and
different and what makes me the same and
now that it's coming more from a place
of curiosity rather than I don't know
feeling broken because I was different
in some way there is a power there and
every time I've learned about new traits
that autistic people have well they're
not new traits but they're new to me
oppositional defiance disorder which i
think is maybe called something else now
but I'm like yeah right and someone
tells me to do something I wanted you
the exact opposite
I cannot own that and be like no listen
to your own internal guide don't not do
something because someone tells you to
but also don't do something cuz somebody
tells you to that more and more autistic
people there's a higher per capita
percent of people who are queer and
asexual in the autistic community and
those are things that I definitely am so
I am gonna end this here cuz I really
need to cough and I don't want a call
from camera and we're at the 6 minute
mark so this is a bit of my autistic
journey which is interwoven with
everything else